

MD. LUTFUL KABIR

Specialized in Compensation & Benefit, HR

Operations, HRIS and HR Analytics

Contact Info:

Mobile: 01914379839 e-mail: lutful.k@live.com Mirpur-02, Dhaka-1216

HR Professional with more than 13 years of experience in Telco, Oil & Gas and in Manufacturing Industry. Experienced in supervising all functions of HR department with ample experience in IT, Accounts, Procurement, Inventory Management and Repair & Preventive Maintenance of heavy and light vehicles.

Career Objective:

To pursue and retain such career where it is possible to prove the working excellence by contributing the knowledge and experience with honesty, punctuality and sincerity.

Career Summary:

Manager, HR - "Fiber@Home Ltd." (Bangladesh, Largest NTTN Company of the Country") – At Present.

Deputy Manager, HR - "Fiber@Home Ltd." (Promoted to Manager) – 2 Years

Assistant Manager, HR - "Fiber@Home Ltd." (Promoted to Deputy Manager) - 1 Year

HR Specialist - "Mizat Al-Khaleej Holding Co." (KSA) – 8 Years

Administrator - "Faysal M Qahtani Sons Co." (**KSA**) – 2 Years

Sales Promotion Officer - "Trust Bank Limited" (Bangladesh) – 1/2 Year

Professional Expertise

HR Functional

- Compensation & Benefit
- Performance Appraisal
- HR Operations
- Recruitment
- Organization Development
- Training & Development
- HR Analytics

ERP Solutions

JD Edwards (Oracle)

- Human Capital Mgt.
- Asset Master

Resort ERP

- HR Module

F@H HRIS

- HR Module

Software & Application

- MS Excel (Advance Level)
- Power BI (Intermediate)
- Adobe Acrobat Professional
- ACDSee Professional

Professional Experience

Manager, HR | Fiber@Home Limited | February, 2022 – Continuing

Address: House: 7/B, Road: 13, Gulshan: 1, Dhaka-1212

Duties/Responsibilities

- **1. Compensation & Benefit:** Supervise payroll, Festival Bonus, final settlement, WPPF, Incentive Calculation, Annual Leave Encashment, Eid Holiday Bill and oversee other activities such as, PF, Life Insurance, Employee Banking, Corporate Mobile & SMS Bill Management and all other C&B services.
- **2. Organization Development:** Actively engaged in developing new policies and revising existing policies depending on the concurrent business practices, observations and requirement from management.
- **3. Annual Performance Appraisal:** Responsible for all necessary data collection, consolidation of increment and performance feedback from all head of departments, prepare calculation & final recommendation template for management. After approval prepare increment/promotion letters and update employee database.

4. HRIS Development:

- 4.1 Analyze and define requirements of the new modules in HRIS to Software Team (i.e., KPI, Work Activity/Task Management, Management Action Point (Meeting Minute) Management etc.)
- 4.2 Find developmental scope and collect user responses for existing modules, reporting formats and ensure its application after UAT.
- **4.3 Ensure Employee Data Integrity in HR Database:** Periodically verify data accuracy if HR database is updated according to change logs, office communications, departmental changes and management approvals.

Professional Expertise

Procurement & Store Mgt.

- -Requisition Process
- Purchase Order (PO)
- Work Order (WO)
- Inventory Management
- Store Management

Vehicle & Equipment (Light & Heavy)

- Supervise Repair
- Preventative Maintenance

Education Background:

Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)

Human Resources Management (HRM) Daffodil International

University (Dhaka)

Year # 2007, CGPA # 3.49 out of 4.00

Professional Certification:

Advance Certificate for Management Professionals (ACMP 4.0)

IBA, Dhaka University
June 16, 2020 to October 7,
2020 (4 Months)

Trainings Attended

HR Audit Master Class BD Jobs, 1 Day (8 Hours)

Bangladesh Labor Law 2006 with Labor Rules 2015 & Amendment 2018

BDJobs, 4 Days (16 Hours)

Professional Experience (Cont.)

- **5. HR Analytics & Reporting:** Prepare reporting formats for all functions of HR to show present status and forecast the upcoming using MS Excel.
- **5.1 For Recruitment Team:** Headcount Analysis (preset, vacant, under process, budgeted & non-budgeted including recruitment target vs achievement), Interview panel member selection (functional, cross functional & non-functional according to level of recruitment), employee turnover (department, function & level wise) and other ad-hoc repots.
- **5.2** For HR Operations Team: Daily/weekly/monthly level wise and individual attendance trend analysis, short working hour report, Annual/Earn leave carry forward report, AGM & Above Leave request and approval request report
- **5.3 For Training & Development Team:** Competency Gap Analysis report for Training Need Assessment (TNA). Yearly and periodical training calendar and budget. Quarterly/annually training target vs completion report with pre and post training assessment.
- **5.4 For Performance Evaluation Team:** Track and report performance trend of all employees form the collected data of MPE (Monthly Performance Evaluation) by selecting different period range and achievement grade.
- **5.5 Adhoc Reports:** Prepare different analytical reports on adhoc basis as per management's or head of the department's requirement.

Deputy Manager (2.8 Yrs) | Fiber@Home Ltd. | Sep, 2019 – Dec, 2021

Duties/Responsibilities:

Core Responsibilities:

- a) Responsible to Lead Compensation & Benefit (C&B) where the activities include Payroll Management Employee Final Settlement Festival Bonus WPPF (Workers Profit Participation Fund) Annual Leave Encashment PF (Provident Fund) Employee Banking Corporate SIM & SMS (AdReach) Management Employee Life & Medical Insurance Any C&B Related Employee Services (i.e., Confirmation & Contract Extension, Salary Certificate, Payslip etc.)
- b) Responsible to Improve HRMS (bring dynamism in existing modules and add/implement new Module/Sub-Modules) Provide full analytical support in (i) Annual Performance Appraisal (ii) Training Need Assessment (iii) KPI (iv) Salary Benchmarking and in any HR Reporting.

Ad-hoc Responsibility:

Prepare various report for MCM (Management Committee Meeting)
 Policy amendment & development ● Provide Training on MS Excel ●
 Participate in Disciplinary Investigation ● Provide Employee info or report to others departments when requested.

Management Skills:

- » Critical Thinking
- » Strategic Planning
- » Team Management
- » Leadership
- » Problem Solving
- » Team Player

Language Proficiency:

Language Speak Write Read
 English High High High
 Hindi/ Urdu High — —
 Arabic Low — Med
 Bangla Native

Outdoor Interest:

- » Fishing
- » Playing Cricket
- » Playing Badminton
- » Swimming
- » Travelling

Personal Detail:

- » Date of Birth # 08/08/1985
- » Gender # Male
- » Status # Married
- » Dependent # 03
- » Religion # Islam

Name

- » Passport # Yes (Valid)
- » Driving License # Yes (BD & Saudi)
- » Residence # Mirpur 02, Dhaka

Professional Experience (Cont.)

Asst. Manager (1 Year) | Fiber@Home Ltd. | Jul, 2018 - Aug, 2019

Duties/Responsibilities:

Responsible to Lead HR Operations: ● Attendance & Leave Management ● HR Database ● HR Services ● C&B Support ● Business & ID Card Request

Disciplinary & Grievance Management: ● Conduct or Facilitate

Investigation ● Report preparation

HR Specialist | Mizat Al-Khaleej Holding Co. (KSA) | Jan 2010 - Mar, 2018

(Group of Company - Eight Business Units - Total Emp. 2700+)

Address: Dammam 2nd Industrial Area, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA)

Core Responsibility

• Payroll • Performance Appraisal and • Supervise all Functions of HR except Employee Relation of mainly Saudi employees & Saudization.

Other Responsibilities:

(a) Reporting on half year & yearly Provision (Salary, benefit & all employee related expenses; i.e, medical, travel expense, all permit renewal etc.)

Administrator | Faysal M. Qahtani Sons Co. (KSA) | Jul, 2008 - Dec, 2009

Address: Rakha, Alkhobar Dammam, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA)

Duties/Responsibilities

As Administrator

- (a) Handle all employee related issues (i.e; Approve Timesheet, Transfer, Vacation Scheduling etc.) of Repair & Maintenance Division's employees.
- (b) Administer Material Procurement (Requisition & Purchase Order).
- (c) Report on Vehicle & Equipment Maintenance & Repair status.
- (d) Report on material store inventory status

As Project Accountant

(a) Handle Repair & Maintenances Petty Cash Account (b) Selling of any Junk/Scrap Item

As IT Support

(a) Install operating system & software (b) Install or assemble new system or replace defective computer hardware (c) Notify any connectivity failure in VSAT & and help re-establishing connectivity.

Sales Promotion Officer | Trust Bank Limited | Jan, 2008 - Jul, 2008

Reference – 1 (From Prev. Company)

: Ahmad Ajmy

Organization: Mizat Al-Khaleej Holding Co.

Designation: HR Manager

Address: Dammam 2nd Industrial City, KSA.

Phone (Off.) : +966 13 8082071

Mobile : +966 54 042 9263

e-mail : aajmy@mizat.com.sa

Relation: Professional

Reference - 2 (From Present Company)

Md. Mizanur Rahman Fiber@Home Limited Assistant General Manager

House# 7/B, Road# 13, Dhaka-1212

+880 966 677 6677 +880 184 710 2206

mizanur.rahman@fiberathome.net

Professional

Md. Lutful Kabir